<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Long Short Strategies</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Long Short Strategies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Year end targets for S&amp;P 500 Index</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-18-year_end_target/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-18-year_end_target/</guid>
      <description>Updated as of March 2019.
Presenting today the year end targets for 2019, by wall street analysts.
{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;filter&#34;:&#34;none&#34;,&#34;caption&#34;:&#34;Wall Street targets for 2019&#34;,&#34;data&#34;:[[&#34;Morgan Stanley*&#34;,&#34;Goldman Sachs&#34;,&#34;Credit Suisse&#34;,&#34;Deutsche Bank&#34;,&#34;Bank of America Merrill Lynch&#34;,&#34;Citigroup&#34;,&#34;UBS&#34;,&#34;BMO&#34;,&#34;JPMorgan Chase&#34;,&#34;Oppenheimer&#34;,&#34;Fundstrat Global Advisors&#34;,&#34;Wells Fargo Investment Institute&#34;,&#34;CFRA*&#34;,&#34;BNY Mellon Wealth Management&#34;,&#34;Canaccord Genuity&#34;,&#34;RBC Capital Markets&#34;,&#34;BTIG&#34;,&#34;Bernstein&#34;,&#34;Barclays&#34;],[&#34;Mike Wilson&#34;,&#34;David Kostin&#34;,&#34;Jonathan Golub&#34;,&#34;Binky Chadha&#34;,&#34;Savita Subramanian&#34;,&#34;Tobias Levkovich&#34;,&#34;Keith Parker&#34;,&#34;Brian Belski&#34;,&#34;Dubravko Lakos-Bujas&#34;,&#34;John Stoltzfus&#34;,&#34;Thomas Lee&#34;,&#34;Scott Wren&#34;,&#34;Sam Stovall&#34;,&#34;Jeff Mortimer&#34;,&#34;Tony Dwyer&#34;,&#34;Lori Calvasina&#34;,&#34;Julian Emanuel&#34;,&#34;Noah Weisberger&#34;,&#34;Maneesh Deshpande&#34;],[2750,2850,3000,3000,3000,2800,3150,2950,3000,3000,3025,2850,3000,2850,3200,2890,3000,3000,3000],[162,150,161.5,162,153,153,157,158,153,146,147,152,156.2,152.5,160,151,150,160,162.6],[16.98,19,18.58,18.52,19.61,18.3,20.06,18.67,19.61,20.55,20.58,18.75,19.21,18.69,20,19.14,20,18.75,18.45]],&#34;container&#34;:&#34;\n \n \n Firm\n Analyst\n 2019 Target\n S&amp;amp;P 500 Earnings\n S&amp;amp;P 500 PE ratio\n \n \n&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year end targets for S&amp;P 500 Index</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-11-year_end_target/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-11-year_end_target/</guid>
      <description>Presenting today the year end targets for 2019, by wall street analysts.
{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;filter&#34;:&#34;none&#34;,&#34;caption&#34;:&#34;Wall Street targets for 2019&#34;,&#34;data&#34;:[[&#34;Morgan Stanley*&#34;,&#34;Goldman Sachs&#34;,&#34;Credit Suisse&#34;,&#34;Deutsche Bank&#34;,&#34;Bank of America Merrill Lynch&#34;,&#34;Citigroup&#34;,&#34;UBS&#34;,&#34;BMO&#34;,&#34;JPMorgan Chase&#34;,&#34;Oppenheimer&#34;,&#34;Fundstrat Global Advisors&#34;,&#34;Wells Fargo Investment Institute&#34;,&#34;CFRA*&#34;,&#34;BNY Mellon Wealth Management&#34;,&#34;Canaccord Genuity&#34;,&#34;RBC Capital Markets&#34;,&#34;BTIG&#34;,&#34;Bernstein&#34;,&#34;Barclays&#34;],[&#34;Mike Wilson&#34;,&#34;David Kostin&#34;,&#34;Jonathan Golub&#34;,&#34;Binky Chadha&#34;,&#34;Savita Subramanian&#34;,&#34;Tobias Levkovich&#34;,&#34;Keith Parker&#34;,&#34;Brian Belski&#34;,&#34;Dubravko Lakos-Bujas&#34;,&#34;John Stoltzfus&#34;,&#34;Thomas Lee&#34;,&#34;Scott Wren&#34;,&#34;Sam Stovall&#34;,&#34;Jeff Mortimer&#34;,&#34;Tony Dwyer&#34;,&#34;Lori Calvasina&#34;,&#34;Julian Emanuel&#34;,&#34;Noah Weisberger&#34;,&#34;Maneesh Deshpande&#34;],[2750,2850,3000,3000,3000,2800,3150,2950,3000,3000,3025,2850,3000,2850,3200,2890,3000,3000,3000],[162,150,161.5,162,153,153,157,158,153,146,147,152,156.2,152.5,160,151,150,160,162.6],[16.98,19,18.58,18.52,19.61,18.3,20.06,18.67,19.61,20.55,20.58,18.75,19.21,18.69,20,19.14,20,18.75,18.45]],&#34;container&#34;:&#34;\n \n \n Firm\n Analyst\n 2019 Target\n S&amp;amp;P 500 Earnings\n S&amp;amp;P 500 PE ratio\n \n \n&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple lowers revenue forecast</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-02-aapl-stock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-02-aapl-stock/</guid>
      <description>Last evening after market close, Apple lowered their revenue forecast, for Q1 2019. On an interview with Josh Lipton from CNBC, Apple CEO Tim Cook, explained/blamed the the US China trade war for lower iPhone sales. The news came as a shock to the market, an immediately the stock plunged from $158 to $145.
Right now it is trading around $143 which is 9% drop from yesterday.
Performance since 2005Recent performance has been lackluster compared to the pastApple has had phenomenal returns since 2008 financial crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Markets and Important Levels</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-03-major-mkt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-03-major-mkt/</guid>
      <description>On January 2nd, Apple warned a slowdown in iPhone sales forecast and as a result the stock was down almost 10%. Apple’s weakness has affected all major US markets. All the major US markets are now below their key support area. Below we will look at all the major index charts and their key support levels.
Dow Jones Index ETF (DIA)S&amp;amp;P 500 Index ETF (SPY)Nasdaq 100 ETF (QQQ)Russell 2000 ETF (IWM)US Markets are losing major support areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Major Asset class performance</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-02-world-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-02-world-markets/</guid>
      <description>Year 2018 has concluded and its time to reflect back and see what happened this year. We began the year on a positive note, but then by February the market sold off and since then S&amp;amp;P 500 moved sideways between 2500 on the low end to 2940 on the high end. The the range was extended on the lower end when we broke the 2500 support level after the FED hike and the “hawkish” press conference by Jerome Powell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio Positions Update</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-31-portfolio-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-31-portfolio-positions/</guid>
      <description>On October 3rd we published our stock portfolio positions. Q4 of 2018 saw large pullback in the markets. In hindsight it appears that October 2018 may have put in a top (at least until we see that level breached). Given the recent pullback and the uncertainty in the future, we have sold all our stock positions today and switched all our portfolios into bonds. We invested 100% our portfolios in Aggregate Bond Index ETF (symbol AGG)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S&amp;P 500 Analysis December 2018</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-27-sp500_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-27-sp500_analysis/</guid>
      <description>In the last post we discussed the recent sell off in the US equity markets. In this post we will dig deeper and see how individual components of the market performed this year.
First we will begin by looking at the components that make up the S&amp;amp;P 500 index and the returns for 2018.
S&amp;amp;P 500 Components{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;filter&#34;:&#34;none&#34;,&#34;caption&#34;:&#34;S&amp;amp;P 500 Components Data&#34;,&#34;data&#34;:[[&#34;Microsoft Corporation&#34;,&#34;Apple Inc.&#34;,&#34;Amazon.com Inc.&#34;,&#34;Berkshire Hathaway Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Market and Interest Rates Since 2007</title>
      <link>/post/bonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bonds/</guid>
      <description>Volatility is back in the stock markets. In the past we have pointed out the divergence between the US markets and the World stock markets. It is now clear that this disconnection has now resolved itself with the sell-off in the US markets. YTD the US stock market is down about 7%. The month December 2018 saw its worst performance in since the great depression. It was at one point down almost 18%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home builders stocks</title>
      <link>/post/home-builders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/home-builders/</guid>
      <description>2018 has not been a good year for equities. One sector in particular has come under enormous pressure. Home builder stocks are now firmly into bear market. In this article we will try to analyze this sector and see if there is an opportunity to invest or stay away from these stocks.
Lets begin by looking at the overall housing sector.
The sector is highly volatile and cyclical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FANG Stocks</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-14-fang-perf-ytd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-14-fang-perf-ytd/</guid>
      <description>FAANG stock performance since October 1, 2018. We have seen major losses since October 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Banks</title>
      <link>/post/world-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/world-banks/</guid>
      <description>The US stocks market are in a coorection territory now. They are down more than 10% in the last two months. One of the major sectors has been trending lower throughout 2018. The financials sector is in a bear market. The major banks around the world are looking weak. Initially investors dismissed these concerns as company specific. Goldman Sachs was tangled in the 1MDB scandal. Then there European banks such as Deutche Bank and Credit Suisse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Markets</title>
      <link>/post/world-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/world-markets/</guid>
      <description>Market Review 2018We began this year on a high note. Markets around the world rallied 7 to 8% in January. But February saw a quick 10% correction. Since then the stock markets have mostly gone sideways. But the volatility has increased a lot in the last few weeks.
Below are some reasons for the sideways market
Trade warsSince Donald Trump took control of the White House he had been eager to reduce the US trade deficits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red October</title>
      <link>/post/2018-10-25-sp500_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-10-25-sp500_analysis/</guid>
      <description>For the third quarter of 2018 S&amp;amp;P 500 rallied almost 8.5% and was up almost 10% for 2018. But all that has changed since the beginning of Q4 2018 in October. We will begin by looking at the yearly performance of S&amp;amp;P 500 so far.
As we can see that October saw a severe fall in stock market price. We lost almost 10% and wiped off all the gains for the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mega Millions</title>
      <link>/post/mega-millions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mega-millions/</guid>
      <description>It was lottery fever in America and the recent Mega Million lottery jackpot grew to almost $1.6 billion. Its the largest jackpot in the lottery’s history. The winning numbers were drawn yesterday, and the winner is from North Carolina. We may not know who the winner is since North Carolina’s law allows lottery winners to stay anonymous.
The number $1.6 billion may sound a lot (and it is), after all this person(s), will be 1477th richest in the world according to Forbes ranking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold Trade update</title>
      <link>/post/gold-trade-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gold-trade-update/</guid>
      <description>On October 19, 2018 our Gold ETF options expired out of the money and as a result we lost our premium which was our maximum loss on the trade.
We entered the trade on August 6, 2018 and chose October as our expiration month. When we entered the trade, GLD was trading around $114 and today is it around $116.
Even though the price of GLD is above its price on August 6th, it is not high enough to be profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio Positions</title>
      <link>/post/portfolio-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/portfolio-positions/</guid>
      <description>Our Current PortfoliosStarting this quarter we will publish the the list of our portfolios where we are investing our money. These portfolios are constructed for investors with different levels of risks and return objectives. We have initially invested $10 million in each portfolio and we will monitor the progress as we go along. These portfolios were constructed on October 3rd 2018 and the purchase prices are from that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold investor&#39;s lost decade</title>
      <link>/post/gold-investor-s-lost-decade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gold-investor-s-lost-decade/</guid>
      <description>On September 15, 2008 investment bank Lehman Brothers announced bankruptcy. This event was the largest bankruptcy in US history and pushed the world economies in deep recessions. Today is the 10 year anniversary of this event. We wanted to reflect back on this event and see how the markets have performed since the bankruptcy in 2008.
It was a tough time for investors and many panicked and sold their stock holdings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S&amp;P 500 Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-17-sp500_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-17-sp500_analysis/</guid>
      <description>How has S&amp;amp;P 500 performed so far in 2018. We can start by looking at the S&amp;amp;P 500 chart below.
We can see from the chart that the S&amp;amp;P 500 is up about 6.5% since January. The price action in this chart has been sideways. We are stuck in a range 250 and 285. After big gains in 2017 the market seems to be consolidating at these new all time highs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold trade update</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-13-gold_trade_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-13-gold_trade_update/</guid>
      <description>The Turkish currency depreciation which was a slow moving event for the past two years is now front and center in the financial world. The relations between US and Turkey have been deteriorating and Turkey which is a NATO member is looking for new friends. In light of all this our long gold trade has been performing poorly. We put on that trade last Monday (August 6) and since then Gold prices have fallen 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkey Currency Crisis</title>
      <link>/post/turkey-currency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/turkey-currency/</guid>
      <description>Turkey Currency crisisThe emerging markets are spiraled into chaos and crisis and leading the way is Turkey. The country has been tackling one crisis after another. In 2016 the there was an attempt of military coup which was put down by the people of Turkey. Since then the current president of Turkey Erdogan has consolidated his hold at the top. He has purged many opponents and the recent elections has emboldened his hold at the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLT trade - Iron Condor</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-08-tlt-iron-condors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-08-tlt-iron-condors/</guid>
      <description>Today we executed a trade to sell both call and put verticals on the underlying TLT etf (Long US government bonds etf). For the trade to make money, both legs of the trade need to expire worthless. First lets start by looking at the historical returns and volatility of Long Bonds since summer of 2016.
Interest rates made their lows in the summer of 2016 and since then rates have been moving higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold Trade Idea</title>
      <link>/post/gld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gld/</guid>
      <description>A potential trade idea that we executed today was being long Gold. First lets see how the shiny object has performed since 2010 versus the dollar.
Its clear from the chart that both assets move in opposite directions (most of the time). After the huge run in price in Gold from 2009 t0 2013, it saw a crash in 2014. Since then its been sideways and range bound trading between $1300 to $1200.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/</guid>
      <description>This is where you will find code in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FANG Stocks</title>
      <link>/post/fang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fang/</guid>
      <description>FAANG stock performance since July 1, 2018
With Netflix and Facebook both suffering major losses, all eyes will be on Apple as it races to be the first company with a $1 Trillion valuation.
How have the FAANG stocks performed YTD
Netflix and Amazon have clearly dominated the large cap stocks. This has been a terrible year of performance for managers who make a living by shorting “bubble basket stocks”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bond Market</title>
      <link>/post/bond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bond/</guid>
      <description>Year 2018 has not been a good one for the bond investors. Since the summer of 2017, interest rates have been rising.
The long term interest rates had been trending lower since 1980s. In the chart above rates reached a high of 8% and since then they kept making lower lows. Currently the ten year rates are near the an important key level at 3%. From here the future path interest will decide which way the trend moves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook disappoints! Stock down 20%</title>
      <link>/post/facebook-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/facebook-idea/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Facebook reported their earnings after market hours and investors were not pleased. They sent the stock down almost 25% at one point. Right now the stock is down about 20%. We wanted to check if this was the worst performance for Facebook stock since the IPO
This is the worst one day performance for Facebook since its IPO. After its IPO Facebook stock was under heavy pressure and it continued to slide down for several days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interest Rates and Bear Markets</title>
      <link>/post/int_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/int_rates/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect Market Valuations?It has been said many times that it is impossible to predict a bear market. Many on Wall Street spend enormous amount of time and money on this very activity. Although it may be difficult to predict the bear market one can evaluate the conditions that could lead to a bear market. What do I mean by that?
Lets imagine a bridge that carries thousands of vehicles across from one end to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/post/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/test/</guid>
      <description>This is a shebang line post. It is for testing the pipelines and making sure everything look ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome This website was built to log financial events, portfolio strategies and trading ideas. This website is not intended to provide financial advice. Financial assets such as company stocks are risky. They can depreciate in value and cause permanent loss of capital. It is always important to consult a financial advisor to discuss whether a certain investment is suitable for you.
If you would like to learn, then a fake money account is more appropriate for learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showcase</title>
      <link>/showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/showcase/</guid>
      <description>Header 2 Backup two-step verification breach, anonymous terminal traffic worm virus reboot fsociety dat file. Traffic fsociety malware 100 terabytes system hack, delete brute-force cyber security fiber connection connect code worm wipe. Cyber security off the grid delete IP decrypt, nodes connect password 100 terabytes RUDY attack malicious code rootkit gigabit speed. Tor connect network, intercepting traffic off the grid IP protocol password.
 Backup DDoS attack rootkit nodes disconnect website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>+++title = “Portfolio”date = “2018-07-27”author = “Team Greenleaf”+++
This is where you will find portfolio positions in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>