<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markets on Long Short Strategies</title>
    <link>/tags/markets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markets on Long Short Strategies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home builders stocks</title>
      <link>/post/home-builders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/home-builders/</guid>
      <description>2018 has not been a good year for equities. One sector in particular has come under enormous pressure. Home builder stocks are now firmly into bear market. In this article we will try to analyze this sector and see if there is an opportunity to invest or stay away from these stocks.
Lets begin by looking at the overall housing sector.
The sector is highly volatile and cyclical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Banks</title>
      <link>/post/world-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/world-banks/</guid>
      <description>The US stocks market are in a coorection territory now. They are down more than 10% in the last two months. One of the major sectors has been trending lower throughout 2018. The financials sector is in a bear market. The major banks around the world are looking weak. Initially investors dismissed these concerns as company specific. Goldman Sachs was tangled in the 1MDB scandal. Then there European banks such as Deutche Bank and Credit Suisse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Markets</title>
      <link>/post/world-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/world-markets/</guid>
      <description>Market Review 2018We began this year on a high note. Markets around the world rallied 7 to 8% in January. But February saw a quick 10% correction. Since then the stock markets have mostly gone sideways. But the volatility has increased a lot in the last few weeks.
Below are some reasons for the sideways market
Trade warsSince Donald Trump took control of the White House he had been eager to reduce the US trade deficits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>