<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gld on Long Short Strategies</title>
    <link>/tags/gld/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gld on Long Short Strategies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/gld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold Trade update</title>
      <link>/post/gold-trade-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gold-trade-update/</guid>
      <description>On October 19, 2018 our Gold ETF options expired out of the money and as a result we lost our premium which was our maximum loss on the trade.
We entered the trade on August 6, 2018 and chose October as our expiration month. When we entered the trade, GLD was trading around $114 and today is it around $116.
Even though the price of GLD is above its price on August 6th, it is not high enough to be profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold trade update</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-13-gold_trade_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-13-gold_trade_update/</guid>
      <description>The Turkish currency depreciation which was a slow moving event for the past two years is now front and center in the financial world. The relations between US and Turkey have been deteriorating and Turkey which is a NATO member is looking for new friends. In light of all this our long gold trade has been performing poorly. We put on that trade last Monday (August 6) and since then Gold prices have fallen 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold Trade Idea</title>
      <link>/post/gld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gld/</guid>
      <description>A potential trade idea that we executed today was being long Gold. First lets see how the shiny object has performed since 2010 versus the dollar.
Its clear from the chart that both assets move in opposite directions (most of the time). After the huge run in price in Gold from 2009 t0 2013, it saw a crash in 2014. Since then its been sideways and range bound trading between $1300 to $1200.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>